portalclaims.com 2013-10-26

# Privacy Policy | Portal Claims

## Information About Our Organisation And Web Site

Modern information and communication technologies play a fundamental role in the activities of an organisation like Portal Claims LLP. This Statement sets out our policy relating to the privacy of our customers' data.

We are based in United Kingdom and our principal activity is assisting people who have been mis-sold endowment policies, mis-sold payment protection insurance policies and received excessive bank charges to claim compensation.

Our privacy policy covers Portal Claims LLP and its Web site, www.portalclaims.com. If you have any comments about this Privacy Policy, our Data Controller is Paul Wheal. You may email him at info@portalclaims.com or write to him at Portal Claims LLP, Portal House, Sunderland Quay, Rochester, Kent ME2 4HN.

You also have the right to contact the Information Commissioner about matters relating to your private data. Details on how you may do this can be found at [www.ico.gov.uk](http://www.ico.gov.uk/ "Information Commissioner")

## Providing Visitors With Anonymous Access

You can access our Web site home page and browse our site without disclosing your personal data.

## The Services And Links Of Our Website

Our Web site does not enable our visitors to communicate with other visitors or to post information to be accessed by others.

Our Web site may include links to third party Web service providers. Portal Claims LLP is not responsible for the content of third party Websites.

## Automatic Collection Of Information

We do not automatically log personal data nor do we link information automatically logged by other means with personal data about specific individuals.

## Use of Cookies

Our website makes use of cookies in order for the contact forms (such as the claim form) to work. These cookies are used are for the sole purpose of carrying out the transmission of a communication over an electronic communications network and, as such, subscriber consent is not required prior to their use. We do not link non-personal information stored in cookies with other personal data about specific individuals. You may delete and block all cookies from this site, but the contact forms will no longer work.

In addition, both Google Analytics and Google Adwords are linked to this site, and both of these services use cookies. To opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics across all websites visit <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>. To opt out of being tracked by Google Adwords across all websites visit <http://www.google.com/privacy/ads/>. 

## Data Collection And Purpose Specification

We collect the personal data that you may volunteer while using our services. We may also collect information about you from other sources, such as public records or bodies, or private organisations (like your endowment company). We do not collect or use personal data for any purpose other than the administration of your Endowment claim(s).

## Data Held

The following personal data about you may be collected and held on our database. This will either have come directly from you or from other private organisations (such as your endowment company):

Name, Gender, Address, Telephone, Fax, Email, Relevant and specific details about your financial situation (e.g. the details of your endowment policy), Identifiers assigned by public bodies (such as your National Insurance number)

## Disclosure And Visitors' Choice

We may pass your personal data to relevant third parties to enable us to process your claim(s).

## Confidentiality/Security

We do not give visitors to our Web site the option of using a secure transmission method to send us their personal data. We have implemented security policies, rules and technical measures to protect the personal data that we have under our control from: unauthorised access, improper use or disclosure, unauthorised modification, unlawful destruction or accidental loss.

All our employees and Data Processors, who have access to, and are associated with the processing of personal data, are obliged to respect the confidentiality of our visitors' personal data.

We ensure that your personal data will not be disclosed to State institutions and authorities except if required by law or other regulation.

## Access To The Personal Data We May Hold About You

You can ask us, in writing (via post or email) for details of what personal data we hold about you. Upon receipt of such a written request and proof of your identity, we will provide you with a readable copy of the personal data which we keep about you. We will do this within a month, and reserve the right to charge you £10 for this information. We allow you to challenge the data that we hold about you and, where appropriate, you may have the data:

Erased/Rectified or amended/Completed

We do not reserve the right to refuse to provide you with a copy of your personal data.

## Children's Privacy

We do not knowingly collect personal data from children.

## Privacy Compliance

This privacy policy is compliant with the United Kingdom's Data Protection Act (1998), The European Data Protection Directive 95/46/EC and the Organisation for Economic Cooperation and Development's guidelines for Privacy Policies.
